<!--
  ~ Copyright (c) 2018 by siggel <siggel-apps@gmx.de>
  ~
  ~     This file is part of Coordinate Joker.
  ~
  ~     Coordinate Joker is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  ~     it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  ~     the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  ~     (at your option) any later version.
  ~
  ~     Coordinate Joker is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  ~     but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  ~     MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  ~     GNU General Public License for more details.
  ~
  ~     You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  ~     along with Coordinate Joker.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
  -->

<resources>
    <string name="string_help">
        <![CDATA[
        <h1>General function</h1>
        <p>
        Hopefully usage of Coordinate Joker is rather self explanatory:
        </p>
        <p>
        <b>1. </b>Enter <b>coordinates</b>,<br>
        <b>2. Possibly</b> enter <b>projection</b> (mind for unit Meter or feet!), otherwise leave
        distance and azimuth 0,<br>
        <b>3. </b>Set <b>value range</b> for x and<br>
        <b>4. </b>send to your desired App with \"<b>View</b>\" or \"Send\".<br>
        </p>
        <h2>Entering formulas</h2>
        <p>
        When entering formulas you need to pay attention to the following rules: Coordinate Joker
        replaces the value x within the formulas with the desired values. That operation must result
        in a mathematically correct formula or number. Therefore an expression like
        <b><font color=\"green\">12.3x5</font></b>
        will work for positive x, but an expression like
        <b><font color=\"red\">12.3(4+x)5</font></b>
        unfortunately won\'t. Strictly speaking, the Geocaching minutes are a decimal number with
        3 decimal places:
        1*10 + 2*1 + 3*0.1 + (4+x)*0.01 + 5*0.001.
        You could therefore write the formula like e.g.:
        <b><font color=\"green\">12.305 + (4+x)*0.01</font></b> for Coordinate Joker being able
        to solve it.
        In addition to the four basic operations Coordinate Joker supports the following mathematical
        operations: <br>
        y^z: exponential function <br>
        y%z: modulo operation <br>
        abs(y): absolute value <br>
        acos(y): arccosine <br>
        asin(y): arcsine <br>
        atan(y): arctangent <br>
        cbrt(y): cubic root <br>
        ceil(y): next higher integer <br>
        cos(y): cosine <br>
        cosh(y): hyperbolic cosine <br>
        exp(y): exponential function (base e) <br>
        floor(y): next lower integer <br>
        log(y): natural logrithm (base e) <br>
        log10(y): decimal logarithm (base 10) <br>
        log2(y): binary logarithm (base 2) <br>
        sin(y): sine <br>
        sinh(y): hyperbolic sine <br>
        sqrt(y): square root <br>
        tan(y): tangent <br>
        tanh(y): hyperbolic tangent <br>
        </p>
        <h2>Reset</h2>
        <p>
        With \"Reset\" you can clear the formula lines. The projection will be reset to 0 and meter
        units. The value range will be preset to rage 0 to 9.
        </p>
        <h1>Export formats</h1>
        <p>
        Within the settings menu you can choose between various export formats and behaviors
        (gpx, kml, kmz, immediate display or sending file).
        <h2>Settings for Locus Map</h2>
        <p>
        <b>All settings \"on\".</b>
        </p>
        <p>
        The delivery settings (all settings \"on\") generates waypoints in kmz-format incl. an own
        marker icon and sends them to all apps, that Android offers for displaying that format
        received in that way. We recommend that you import the points to an own folder which you
        use exclusively for this purpose. Thus all Coordinate Joker waypoints can be easily shown
        or hidden all at once.
        </p>
        <h2>Settings for c:geo</h2>
        <p>
        <b>All settings \"off\".</b>
        </p>
        <p>
        For c:geo we recommend using the gpx-format. Currently c:geo does not accept receiving the
        waypoints directly but wants to read them from a file. Therefore you need to select
        \"off\" for immediate display. The resulting gpx-file then needs to be saved with a file
        explorer (e.g. to you Download folder) and opened afterwards with c:geo. We recommend that
        you import the points to an own folder which you
        use exclusively for this purpose.
        </p>
        <p>
        Notice: Coordinate Joker shall consciously get along without any Android rights and
        therefore does not save to the download or other folders. Instead called apps will receive
        permission to access Coordiante Jokers internally generated files.
        </p>
        <h1>Warnings and Errors</h1>
        <h2>Formula errors</h2>
        <p>
        An error will be shown if the formulas cannot be solved and produce no result.
        It can happen, that some x-values result in valid coordinates, while others don\'t.
        This case will result in a warning about having obtained less points than requested, but the
        valid points will be shown nevertheless.
        </p>
        <h2>Export Problems</h2>
        <p>
        Depending on chosen settings Coordinate Joker sends the resulting waypoints in gpx, kml or
        kmz format to other apps for display. Android will offer apps that claim that they can
        handle that format. So it depends on one hand on your installed apps whether and which apps
        are offered to display the waypoints. On the other hand you decide within the Coordinate
        Joker settings which format will be made available. So don\'t wonder if your favorite
        geocaching app is not offered in the Android app selection menu, maybe it is simply not
        capable to receive the chosen format or is restricted to reading waypoints from file. It may
        even happen that Android does not find any app supporting the format, then you
        will receive an error message instead of the app selector menu. In any case try alternative
        settings to find a solution (or try to proceed like described for c:geo above).
        </p>
        <p>
        A further common problem is that Android may have remembered which app you selected for
        display and does not offer alternatives anymore, so you don\'t need to repeat the selection
        again and again. If you nevertheless want to change to another app, you need to reset that
        remembered association within Android. Details for doing so may vary depending on your
        Android version and flavor.
        </p>
        ]]>
    </string>
</resources>
